Guide to the William Rufus Shafter Papers
Department of Special Collections
- ROLL IV, July 15-August 7, 1898
  Upon the cessation of hostilities, the Americans could turn their attention to the general health of the troops. Yellow fever and malaria had begun to take their toll. The official recommendations for coping with fever are contained in Colonel Greenleaf's Memorandum for Sanitary Precautions in Removing the Army from Its Present Line... dated July 17, 1898. This memorandum admonishes the men to keep clean and to move camp every time a fever case is reported. Another means of wrestling with the fever was suggested by a Mr. Nichols. His intriguing letter of July 26, 1898, suggests that the army employ Dr. F. Smyth-Stuart's cure for yellow fever which was used by the British forces attacking Cuba in 1762.
  The officers were not amused or reassured by either suggestion. It was their opinion that the command would be decimated by the various fevers if it was forced to remain in Cuba. This belief gave rise to the Round Robin letter of August 3, one of the more important documents contained in the Shafter Papers. The letter is notable in that it is a request expressed in mandatory language that the command be removed from Cuba, and it is signed by Shafter's general officers. Its publication by the Associated Press caused great embarrassment to the government and prompted two communications from Secretary Alger. The official telegram of August 11 chastises Shafter for issuing the letter without permission. In a personal note to Shafter, Alger advises him to plead exhaustion as the reason for using such strong terms of address.
  An item in this roll well worth noting is a letterpress copy of a telegram sent by General Linares to the Spanish Minister of War, which describes the position and condition of his suffering troops. He implores the Spanish government to surrender, offering his reputation as a sacrifice for the good of the Mother Country. Shafter, impressed by the poignance of this note, sent it to Secretary Alger as a keepsake.
  The remaining documents on this roll are orders and correspondence concerned with preparations to return home to Montauk Point as per orders dated August 3, 1898.
- ROLL V, August 8-September 25, 1898
  The order to return home was heartily welcomed and promptly obeyed. Orders, correspondence, and lists chronicle the movement of the Fifth Army from Cuba to its disbursement from Montauk Point, Long Island. Inquiries for news of the missing and dead give testimony to the less palatable aspect of war.
  While arranging to transport his troops, Shafter was actively engaged in preparing Santiago de Cuba for the resumption of civilian life. Several reports and letters attest to the fact that this was not to be an easy task. In a report dated August 9, 1898, Judge Advocate Groesbeck recommends complete rehabilitation of the civil and criminal courts in Santiago de Cuba. His report also discusses the sensitive question of appointing a new president of the Supreme Court.
  In a letter of the same date, Shafter laments the large number of highly paid officials who want their jobs back, and refuses to pay the great hordes. His plans for the civilian government of Santiago de Cuba are disclosed in a note of August 16 to Adjutant General Corbin. He informs Corbin that he has arranged for the economical administration of government by abolishing the office of Civil Governor and reducing the number of positions in the Mayor's office, the police department, and the customs houses.
  On August 12, Shafter received the proclamation declaring an armistice between the United States and Spain. A letter from the Cuban leader, Estrada Palma, dated August 13, informed Shafter of his acceptance of that armistice. That same day two notes from Washington apprised him that press censorship had ended, and that arrangements had been made to transport the Spanish prisoners to Spain.
  The sentiments of a Spanish soldier in defeat are expressed in a letter written by Private Pedro López de Castillo of the Spanish Infantry. On the eve of their departure eleven thousand prisoners convey in this missive their respect for the courage of the American soldier; their thanks for the kindness shown the wounded and captured; and their best wishes to a former enemy.
  In a telegram of August 25, Shafter informs Adjutant General Corbin that the command has embarked for Long Island that very morning, and that he intends to leave Cuba before noon. He would return to the United States a hero. Shafter relinquished his command to Major General Henry W. Lawton in General Orders 41, and arrived at Montauk Point by August 31. Shortly thereafter, he wrote to Washington to express his preference to be assigned to the Department of California. That request is coupled with the wish that Majors Noble and Miley, Captain Plummer, and Lieutenant Colonel McClernand be chosen to accompany him to his new post.
  A note from A. C. Sharpe concerning the Society of the Army of Santiago de Cuba, a letter sent by Shafter defending his actions in Cuba, an invitation to speak at the National Peace Jubilee in Chicago, and several congratulatory notes comprise the remainder of this roll.
- ROLL VI, September 26, 1898-March 27, 1945 1860-1906
  Included in this portion of the Collection are photographs, correspondence, speeches, cartoons, maps, and miscellany. Though most of this is related to the Spanish-American War, there are some items which date back as far as 1860.
  Shafter relinquished command of the detention camp at Montauk Point on October 2, 1898, and was temporarily appointed to command the Department of the East. It was at this time that the Committee to Investigate the War turned its attention to Shafter and his command. The Committee investigated, while yellow press journalism provided a showcase which revealed the diversity of opinion regarding the Spanish-American War. Shafter, once an unconditional hero, now had to defend those who transported, docked, supplied, and nursed the command, and his responsibility for their actions. The many letters from his subordinates in Cuba provide information and evidence to support his position. Other letters offer compliments and encouragement.
  After assuming command of the Department of California at the San Francisco Presidio, Shafter's duties included receiving newly arrived veterans from the Philippine Campaign. Thank you notes and testimonial letters from grateful parents and state officials are very prominent in this roll. Business of the Society of the Army of Santiago de Cuba is considered in communications between Shafter and his fellow society members.
  The McKittrick Series includes letters written to his daughter about Shafter, and a biographical sketch prepared for The Michigan Historical Magazine. There is one letter to Mary Shafter McKittrick from her father, which is dated 1898, and several from Edward H. Plummer, which elucidate some points of Shafter's life.
  Several other series of documents are included in this roll. There are speeches made by Shafter at various gatherings which give his view of events in Cuba. Oversized documents, such as appointments to rank, muster-in rolls, and maps, together with miscellaneous keepsakes and photographs illustrate the diverse activities in which Shafter participated. Original cartoons, thought to be drawn by Shafter, reveal the lighter side of army life.
- ROLL VII, 1873-October 24, 1938
  News clippings concerning Shafter's activities comprise about one-fifth of the Collection. The clippings begin with a criticism of MacKenzie's raid into Mexico in 1873, and end with the announcement of the acquisition of the Shafter Papers by Stanford University Libraries in 1938. A substantial number of these deal with Shafter's role in the Spanish-American War.
  Several Cuban newspapers, which date from the period immediately following the war, are included in the Collection. Among them are El Espectador, El Aliuizote, El Parvenir, El Cubano, and The Times, the first American daily paper printed in Cuba.
  The Shafter Scrapbook, though poorly preserved, serves to complete the Collection.
Container List
- Series I - Correspondence
  - February 10, 1862 - May 31, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - April 1 - August 29, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - September 21 - December 22, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - January - June 9, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - July 2 - August 29, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - September 12 - November 30, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - December 1 - December 28, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - January 5, 1878 - May 1897 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - April 1 - April 30, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - May 1 - May 5, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - May 6 - May 8, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - May 8 - May 14, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - May 15 - May 21, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - May 22 - May 24, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - May 25 - May 27, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - May 28 - May 31, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - June 1 - June 4, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - June 5 - June 6, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - June 7 - June 10, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - June 11 - June 20, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - June 21 - June 25, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - June 26 - June 28, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - June 29 - July 1, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - July 2 - July 3, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - July 4 - July 5, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - July 6 - July 8, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - July 9 - July 10, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - July 11 - July 12, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - July 13 - July 14, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - July 15 - July 16, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - July 17 - July 18, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - July 19, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - July 20 - July 21, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - July 22 - July 24, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - July 25 - July 26, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - July 27 - July 30, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - July 31, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - August 1 - August 2, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - August 3 - August 4, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - August 5 - August 7, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - August 8 - August 10, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - August 11 - August 14, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - August 15 - August 18, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - August 19 - August 24, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - August 25 - September 7, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - September 8 - September 12, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - September 13 - September 18, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - September 19 - September 25, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - September 29 - September 30, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - October 1 - October 31, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - November 7 - November 30, 1898 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - December 7 - December 27, 1898 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - January 8 - December 17, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - January 1, 1900 - May 19, 1904 (Box 6, Folder 54)
- Series II - McKittrick
  - May 5, 1897 - March 27, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Series III - Speeches
  - Speeches (Box 6, Folder 56)
- Series IV - Biographical Sketch and Outline
  - Biographical Sketch and Outline (Box 6, Folder 57)
- Series V - Memorabilia and Miscellaneous
  - Awards and Commissions (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Letters Patent and Must-in Rolls (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 60)
- Series VI - Illustrative Material
  - Maps (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Original Sketches and Cartoons (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Photographs (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Cartoons and Portraits (Box 7, Folder 64)
- Series VII - Printed Reference
  - Pamphlets on Cuba (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - News Clippings, 1873 - 1897 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - News Clippings, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - News Clippings, April - June 26, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - News Clippings, July 1898 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - News Clippings, August 1898 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - News Clippings, September 1898 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - News Clippings, October 1898 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - News Clippings, November 1898 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - News Clippings, December 1898 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - News Clippings, January 1899 - October 24, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - News Clippings, Undated (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Cuban Newspapers (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Scrapbook (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Scrapbook Addenda (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Copies (Box 8, Folder 80)
Index
Alger, Russell Alexander, Sect. of War: Roll I: Folder 8, Folder 9, Folder 10, Folder 11; Roll II: Folder 12, Folder 13, Folder 14, Folder 15, Folder 16, Folder 17, Folder 18; Roll III: Folder 19, Folder 20, Folder 21, Folder 22, Folder 23, Folder 24, Folder 25, Folder 26, Folder 27, Folder 28, Folder 29, Folder 30; Roll IV: Folder 31, Folder 32, Folder 33, Folder 34, Folder 35, Folder 36, Folder 37, Folder 39, Folder 40; Roll V: Folder 41, Folder 42, Folder 43, Folder 44, Folder 45; Roll VI: Folder 49, Folder 50, Folder 51, Folder 52, Folder 54, Folder 55, Folder 57
Alicante (U. S. Ship) Roll IV Folder 35, Folder 36, Folder 39, Folder 40 Roll V Folder 41
Allegheny (U. S. Ship) Roll II Folder 16 Roll III Folder 19 Roll IV Folder 31, Folder 36 Roll V Folder 44, Folder 48 Roll VI Folder 52
Allen, James Lt. Col. Roll II Folder 11 Roll III Folder 21, Folder 23
Allen, Henry T. Maj. Roll III Folder 24 Roll IV Folder 30
Almirante Oquenda (Spanish Ship) Roll III Folder 22, Folder 25, Folder 26
Almy, William E. Lt., Aide Roll II Folder 12
Alsalti Chief, Mescaleros Roll I Folder 7
Alvarado (Spanish Ship) Roll IV Folder 31
American Consul at Santiago Consul Holliday Roll VI Folder 54
American Red Cross Society Roll II Folder 11 Roll III Folder 24, Folder 25, Folder 26, Folder 27, Folder 28, Folder 29 Roll IV Folder 30, Folder 31, Folder 32, Folder 33, Folder 34, Folder 35, Folder 36, Folder 37, Folder 38 Roll V Folder 41, Folder 42, Folder 43, Folder 44, Folder 45, Folder 47, Folder 48 Roll VI Folder 56
American Red Cross Relief Station, Long Island Roll V Folder 47
Ames, Adelbert Brig. Gen. Roll IV Folder 31, Folder 35, Folder 37, Folder 38 Roll V Folder 45
Ames, Elwin W. Lt., Asst. Surg. Roll VI Folder 49
Anderson, [?] Commander Royal Swedish Navy Roll VI Folder 52
Anderson, Edward Capt., A. A. G. Roll VI Folder 49
Andrus, Frank B. Lt., Judge Advocate Roll II Folder 14
Annapolis (U. S. Ship) Roll II Folder 16 Roll VI Folder 57
Apache (see Mescalero) Roll I Folder 1, Folder 4, Folder 5, Folder 7
Appel, Aaron H. Maj., Surg. Roll II Folder 17 Roll V Folder 47
Arappehos (Indians) Roll I Folder 2
Arcadia (U. S. Ship) Roll V Folder 41, Folder 42, Folder 43
Archbishop de Santiago de Cuba, Saenz de Urturi y Crespo Roll II Folder 28, Folder 29 Roll IV Folder 37
Areola (Indian leader) Roll I Folder 4
Argonaut (Newspaper) Roll V Folder 45
Arias, Adolfo Lt., Sp. Army Roll III Folder 26
Arias Martinas, Isidros Capt. Sp. Army Roll III Folder 25
Arkansas (U. S. Ship) Roll II Folder 16 Roll IV Folder 36 Roll VI Folder 52
Arizona, State of Roll I Folder 8 Roll VI Folder 53
Armas, Jose de New York Sun Correspondent Roll IV Folder 31
Armstrong, William Roll IV Folder 35
Armstrong, Frank Brig. Gen. Roll IV Folder 30
Army and Marine Hospital Roll V Folder 41
Army and Navy Christian Commission Roll VI Folder 56
The Army and Navy Journal Roll I Folder 8
Arnold, Abraham K. Brig. Gen. Vols. Roll II Folder 16
Articles of Capitulation Roll II Folder 29 Roll IV Folder 30, Folder 38
Ashurst, Henry Speaker of the House, Arizona Roll VI Folder 53
Associated Oil Company (of California) Roll VI Folder 55
Associated Press Roll II Folder 17 Roll VI Folder 54, Folder 57
Astor, John Jacob Lt. Col., I. G. Vols. Roll III Folder 19, Folder 20, Folder 23 Roll IV Folder 31, Folder 32, Folder 38 Roll V Folder 45 Roll VI Folder 52
Auger, Christopher C. Brig. Gen. Roll I Folder 1, Folder 8
Auger, Jacob A. Maj., A. A. G. Roll I Folder 1
Auman, William Maj. Roll IV Folder 31, Folder 37
Austin, Frederick C. Roll II Folder 15
Austria Roll II Folder 16
Ayers, Gordon Roll I Folder 1
Ayling, A. D. A. G. [?] Roll I Folder 8
Bailey, J. Murray G. A. R. Post 2 Roll V Folder 46
Baird, Absolom Brig. Gen. Roll I Folder 1 Roll VI Folder 57
Badger (U. S. Ship) Roll V Folder 43
Bailey, Banks, & Broole Roll VI Folder 53
Baker, Stephan Maj. Roll II Folder 12 Roll IV Folder 31, Folder 37
Baker, Chauncy B. Lt. Roll II Folder 13, Folder 17
Bakersfield, California Roll II Folder 15 Roll III Folder 19 Roll V Folder 42 Roll VI Folder 57
Baldwin, Theodore A. Lt. Col. Roll IV Folder 31, Folder 37, Folder 40 Roll V Folder 41, Folder 42 Roll VI Folder 49
Ballenillas, Don Aurelio Capt., Sp. Army Roll IV Folder 34
Balls Bluff, Battle of Roll I Folder 1 Roll VI Folder 57
Ballston Spa Roll IV Folder 31
Baltimore (U. S. Steamer) Roll V Folder 41
Bancroft (U. S. Ship) Roll II Folder 16 Roll III Folder 20, Folder 21 Roll VI Folder 52
Bandera, Quinton Gen., Cuban Forces Roll IV Folder 36, Folder 40
Baracoa, Cuba Roll I Folder 10 Roll II Folder 18 Roll IV Folder 31, Folder 34, Folder 40 Roll V Folder 42, Folder 43, Folder 44
Barret, Eva H. E. Roll III Folder 27
Barrett, Gregory Capt. Roll V Folder 41
Barry, Thomas H. Roll I Folder 8 Roll IV Folder 33 Roll VI Folder 55
Bartlet, John R. Capt., U. S. N. Roll III Folder 19, Folder 23
Barton, Clara Red Cross Roll III Folder 25, Folder 26, Folder 27, Folder 28 Roll IV Folder 32 Roll V Folder 41, Folder 43
Barton, George De Forest Roll VI Folder 50, Folder 51
Batchelder, Nathan P. Capt. Roll VI Folder 54
Bates, Alfred E. Brig. Gen. Roll II Folder 16
Bates, John C. Brig. Gen. Roll II Folder 11, Folder 16 Roll III Folder 21, Folder 22, Folder 23, Folder 24, Folder 25, Folder 26, Folder 27, Folder 28, Folder 29 Roll IV Folder 31, Folder 33, Folder 34, Folder 35, Folder 36, Folder 38, Folder 39 Roll V Folder 41, Folder 43, Folder 44, Folder 45, Folder 46, Folder 47 Roll VI Folder 51, Folder 54
Bates, Mrs. [J. C.?] Roll I Folder 8
Bay State (Hospital Ship) Roll V Folder 44
Beach, William D. Maj. Roll III Folder 21, Folder 23, Folder 24 Roll IV Folder 31, Folder 37
Beacom, Edward S. Lt. Roll I Folder 2, Folder 4, Folder 7
Bedal, Sylvester S. Asst. Surg. Roll I Folder 7, Folder 8
Bell, Clark Roll VI Folder 52, Folder 53
Bell, George Maj., Gen. Roll III Folder 21
Bell, George Jr. Capt. Roll IV Folder 31
Bell, Horace Roll VI Folder 53
Belknap, William W. Sect. of War, October 1869 - March 1876 Roll I Folder 5
Bellinger, John B. Capt. Roll II Folder 13, Folder 16, Folder 17, Folder 18 Roll III Folder 20 Roll IV Folder 38 Roll V Folder 41
Benham, Daniel W. Col. Roll III Folder 23
Benyaurd, William H. H. Lt. Col. Roll II Folder 13, Folder 15
Berkshire (U. S. Ship) Roll II Folder 16, Folder 18 Roll IV Folder 36, Folder 37, Folder 38, Folder 39, Folder 40 Roll V Folder 44, Folder 45 Roll VI Folder 52
Berlin (U. S. Steamer) Roll IV Folder 33, Folder 35, Folder 38 Roll V Folder 44, Folder 45, Folder 47
Bessie (U. S. Steam Lighter) Roll III Folder 22, Folder 23 Roll IV Folder 38, Folder 39 Roll VI Folder 57
Bierce, Ambrose Roll VI Folder 55
Bisbee, William H. Lt. Col. Roll II Folder 12, Folder 16, Folder 17 Roll III Folder 24 Roll IV Folder 31, Folder 37, Folder 38, Folder 39, Folder 40 Roll V Folder 41, Folder 42, Folder 43, Folder 47
Black, [William Murray] Lt. Col. Roll V Folder 43
Blacks, Citizenship Roll I Folder 1
Blair, Charles A. Govenor, Michigan Roll I Folder 1
Blanco, Ramón Capt., Gen., Sp. Army Roll IV Folder 30, Folder 37 Roll V Folder 42 Roll VI Folder 50, Folder 52
Bliss, Fort (Texas) Roll I Folder 10
Bloom, W. L. (see Scripps - McRae League) Roll II Folder 16
Bloomington Echo (Newspaper) Roll VI Folder 50
Bloxham, William D. Governor, Florida, 1881 - 1885 1897 - 1901 Roll II Folder 13 Roll VI Folder 52
Boer War Roll VI Folder 54
Bonnell, Edwin Roll I Folder 9
Booktown, Siege of Roll I Folder 1
Borrow, Hallot A. Capt. Roll IV Folder 38, Folder 39
Borup, Henry D. Lt. Col. Roll IV Folder 40, Folder 41
Boston, Massachusetts Roll V Folder 46, Folder 47
Boswell, C. A. Judge, Hillsborough County, Florida Roll II Folder 14
Bowen, William S. Newsman Roll V Folder 41
Boyd, Orsemus B. Lt. Roll I Folder 2, Folder 4, Folder 5, Folder 6
Boynton, Charles A. Newsman Roll VI Folder 54
Boynton, Henry M. Col. Roll III Folder 27, Folder 28, Folder 29 Roll IV Folder 30, Folder 31 Roll VI Folder 51
Brady, Jasper E. Capt. Roll II Folder 17
Bravo, Nacarino Judge, Superior Court, Santiago Roll IV Folder 34
Bravo River Roll I Folder 1, Folder 2
Bravo, Sr. Manager, Bank of Spain Roll V Folder 41
Brant, Louis P. Capt. Roll II Folder 10, Folder 12
Breakwater (U. S. Ship) Roll II Folder 16 Roll III Folder 21 Roll IV Folder 36, Folder 38 Roll V Folder 42 Roll VI Folder 52
Breckenridge, Ethelbert L. D. Roll IV Folder 31, Folder 37
Breckinridge, Joseph C. Maj. Gen. Roll II Folder 18 Roll III Folder 20, Folder 29 Roll IV Folder 30 Roll VI Folder 54
Brett, Lloyd M. Capt. Roll III Folder 25 Roll V Folder 46 Roll VI Folder 57
Brice, Stewart M. Capt. Roll II Folder 13, Folder 17 Roll IV Folder 31 Roll VI Folder 50, Folder 52, Folder 54
British Consul Brooks, Ramsden, Mason Roll III Folder 24, Folder 25, Folder 26, Folder 27, Folder 29 Roll IV Folder 30, Folder 35, Folder 37, Folder 39, Folder 40 Roll VI Folder 50, Folder 54
Brooke, William Lt. Roll I Folder 10 Roll II Folder 17 Roll III Folder 21, Folder 22, Folder 23, Folder 25 Roll IV Folder 30, Folder 31, Folder 37 Roll V Folder 48
Brooklyn (U. S. Ship) Roll III Folder 21, Folder 22 Roll VI Folder 52
Brown, Fort Roll I Folder 2
Brown, Mrs. George Roll I Folder 8
Brown, Hugh G. Lt. Roll I Folder 1, Folder 2, Folder 4, Folder 5
Brown, Oscar J. Col. Roll II Folder 15
Bruguetas, Don Ricardo Ensign, Sp. Navy Roll V Folder 44
Bullis, John L. Lt. Roll I Folder 2, Folder 3, Folder 4, Folder 5, Folder 6, Folder 7, Folder 8 Roll IV Folder 37
Bureau of Military Information, Washington Department Roll I Folder 9
Burnham, Austin A. Roll V Folder 58
Burr, Edward Capt. Roll III Folder 26, Folder 28, Folder 29 Roll IV Folder 30, Folder 31, Folder 32, Folder 35
Burrows, Julius C. Senator, Michigan Roll I Folder 8 Roll VI Folder 54
Butcher's Corral Roll I Folder 5
Byram, George L. Lt. Roll III Folder 21
Cabanas, Cuba Roll III Folder 24, Folder 26, Folder 29 Roll IV Folder 30 Roll VI Folder 49, Folder 52
Cabaniss, Archibald A. Lt. Roll II Folder 14 Roll III Folder 20, Folder 23, Folder 29 Roll IV Folder 35
Cabreco, Juan Col., Sp. Army Roll III Folder 26, Folder 28
Cadiz, Fleet of Roll III Folder 19, Folder 20, Folder 21, Folder 22, Folder 23
Cadiz, Spain Roll III Folder 19, Folder 23 Roll IV Folder 35, Folder 36, Folder 39
Caimanera, Cuba Roll IV Folder 33, Folder 35, Folder 36 Roll V Folder 42, Folder 44
Calef, John H. Maj. Roll V Folder 45
California, Department of Roll I Folder 8 Roll V Folder 45, Folder 47 Roll VI Folder 49, Folder 52, Folder 53, Folder 57
California Historical Society Roll I Folder 9
California Supreme Court Roll I Folder 1 Roll VI Folder 57
Campbell, James E. Governor of Ohio 1890 - 1892 Roll V Folder 45
Canada Roll I Folder 8
Canby, James P. Paymaster Roll I Folder 1
Caney, Cuba Roll III Folder 22, Folder 23, Folder 25, Folder 26, Folder 27, Folder 28, Folder 29 Roll IV Folder 30, Folder 36
Canovas, Leon J. Newsman Roll II Folder 17
Capehart, Edward Lt., U. S. N. Roll IV Folder 31, Folder 32
Capitulation Roll III Folder 29 Roll IV Folder 30
Capron, Allyn Capt. Roll I Folder 10 Roll II Folder 14 Roll III Folder 22 Roll IV Folder 31
Capron, Allyn K. Capt. Roll III Folder 21, Folder 22, Folder 23, Folder 28 Roll IV Folder 30 Roll VI Folder 51
Capron, Oliver Capt., 1777 Roll I Folder 8
Captain Sam (U. S. Tug) Roll II Folder 16
Carbaugh, Harvy C. Capt., A. G. Roll II Folder 13 Roll III Folder 25, Folder 28, Folder 29 Roll IV Folder 31, Folder 37
Carpenter, Gilbert S. Lt. Col., Brig. Gen. Roll IV Folder 31, Folder 37 Roll V Folder 47 Roll VI Folder 50
Carpenter, Louis H. Brig. Gen., U. S. V. Roll II Folder 17
Carroll, Henry Lt. Col. Roll II Folder 16 Roll III Folder 23, Folder 26
Carter, Edward C. Maj., Surg. Roll V Folder 42